Rubinow, Isaac Max Papers 5616
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Shimkin, N. - Hadassah Medical Organization, 1923-1926 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  correspondence re financial and other activities of the organization and personal (Shimkin's correspondence in Russian)
- Shroder, William J. - Acting Executive Director, Community Chest of Cincinnati, 1930-1934 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Sk, 1931-1934 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Si, 1912-1935 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  literary correspondence with A.M. Simons, editor, Coming Nation re book reviews, articles on health insurance; correspondence with Mary K. Simkhovitch discusses Abraham Epstein's condition (7/3/35) and routine
- Silver, Abba Hillel - member U.S. Unemployment Commission, 1931-1935 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  correspondence re unemployment insurance e legislation and personal
- Sinclair, Upton, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  correspondence re request by Sinclair for information on living conditions (housing) of poor in Philadelphia for a study and reply by Rubinow
- Sl-Sm, 1901-1936 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  miscellaneous routine correspondence includes correspondence with Sumner Slichter re reprints dealing with unemployment insurance; Munroe Smith re articles in Political Science Quarterly (1901-11) of which he was Editor, lengthy letter of criticism from Rubinow to Smith re article on Russian Trade U.S.
- Slawson, John - Secretary, Jewish Welfare Federation of Detroit, (Rubinow, member of Editorial Board of the Quarterly), 1930-1936 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  re literary and personal
- Sm, 1930-1936 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Smith College, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  re lecture arrangements
- So, 1925-1936 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  personal, literary re social science abstracts; with Walton H. Hamilton, Director Social Security Board re obtaining Rubinow's counsel and help and routine
- Sobeloff, Simon - Chairman, Governor's Committee on Unemployment Insurance and Relief (Maryland), 1931-1935 (Box 9, Folder 32-33)
  re unemployment insurance legislation; Epstein's change of attitude; problems with provisions of the Social Security Act once it passed and routine and personal
- Social Forces, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Social Science Research Council, 1931-1936 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  correspondence re funding for Rubinow1s research study on "The Position of the Jew in the Academic World in America," and routine literary
- Social Security Act - Federal, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  memoranda re meetings of members of the Social Insurance Group; correspondence re principles of the tentative draft with Owen E. Pence
- Socialist Party, 1915-1918 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  correspondence with U. Solomon, NYS Committee, Secretary, re assisting 'Comrade' Shiplakoff in drafting legislative bills on workmen's compensation and unemployment insurance; correspondence with Evans Clark, Research Director, Socialist Aldermanic Delegation, asking Rubinow's assistance in preparing political plank on social insurance for Socialist candidates
- Sp, 1925-1932 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  personal, routine, literary, significant amount of correspondence with Ruth Sperack, Rubinow's secretary, includes letters of recommendation, etc.
- Speaking Engagements, 1997-1923 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  Maimonides Club (Boston), Chicago Forum, Columbia University, Associated Physicians (Long Island), National Conference on Economic Security, Unitarian Church, Hadassah-Women's Zionist Organization, various Hadassah chapters - includes correspondence, programs, broadsides
- St, 1908-1936 (Box 9, Folder 40-41)
  correspondence with Susan Wharton of Starr Centre re offering position of General Secretary to Rubinow; with James Steward and Co. re grain situation in Russia; Amy D. Steinhart re statistics of child welfare in California; correspondence with Ethelbert Stewart, Commissioner USBLS re routine and personal; with Bernard Stone re question of whether or not Rubinow is Executive Director of United Palestine Appeal; personal financial re Studebaker Corporation and other routine and personal
- Statistics, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  statistics from various sources
- Sternin, Nachum, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Stevens, W.H.S. - Special Expert with Federal Trade Commission, 1918-1919 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  re grain exchange investigation and personal
- Stitt, Louise, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  letters of recommendation for L. Stitt re her position with Minimum Fair Wage Board of the Cleaning and Dyeing Industry and other activities of the Board
- Street and Electric Railway Employees of America, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  correspondence re arbitration case of which Rubinow was a member of the Arbitration Board (includes copy of award)
- Survey, 1912-1929 (Box 9, Folder 47-48)
  correspondence re Brewers' Pension Plan, editing various manuscripts before publication and routine literary
- Survey Associates, 1930-1936 (Box 9, Folder 49-51)
  correspondence - editorial, personal, Lundeen Bill (file folder 50), mostly with Paul and Arthur Kellogg
- Su-Sw, 1912-1936 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  routine letter from Hele- Summer (1912); personal, financial and routine correspondence
- Sw-Sz, 1923-1934 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  letter of recommendation for Rubinow by R. Szold (1923) to Commissioner of Labor, NYS and routine
- Szold, Henrietta, 1926-1936 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  correspondence re Hadassah, Zionist Organization of America, German situation, request from Szold for financial support for settlement for German Jewish children in Palestine; correspondence with Mrs. Robert Szold re 70th birthday of Henrietta Szold requesting Rubinow to contribute article for special edition of Hadassah Newsletter dedicated to Henrietta Szold; and personal correspondence
- Szold, Henrietta, 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  issue of Hadassah Newsletter, Dec. 1930 dedicated to Szold; additional issue Dec. 1931+ includes articles by and about Szold; 10 p. manuscript re Szold (Dec. 1935) re 75th birthday; "A birthday tribute to Henrietta Szold," by Rose G. Jacobs, 193^; "Miss Szold as a leader of women," by Lotta Levinsohn, 1930; "Henrietta Szold" by Sarah Kussy, 1931*; article in Boston Evening Transcript Magazine Section, Dec. 1935 re 75th birthday
- Ta, 1929-1936 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  personal and financial correspondence with David Tannenbaum, Director, American Friends of the Hebrew University re gift of Dr. Himowich's library to the University; routine literary; with F. W. Taussig re criticism of old age legislation
- Tamiment Institute, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Te, 1928-1935 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  correspondence with A. Zitron, Secretary of the Teachers League for Academic Freedom re questionnaire sent to Rubinow from the League; personal; correspondence with S.A. Terris re socialization of medicine, official views of B'nai B'rith
- Th-Ti, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  routine literary correspondence and financial; letter to editor Cincinnati Times Star criticizing editorial, "The Risk of an Unemployment Insurance Bill"
- Thomas, Norman, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  correspondence between Thomas (League for Industrial Democracy) and Rubinow re presidential election, luncheon engagements; re anti-Semitic issue raised by Morris Hillquit supporters at Socialist's convention in Milwaukee
- To, 1916-1935 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  correspondence with Lawrence Todd re Meyer London preparation of social insurance bill (1916); personal and routine
- Townsend Plan, 1935-1936 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  articles re the Plan
- Tr, 1914-1933 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  correspondence with A.L. Trachtenberg, Yale University, re literary and routine
- Tyson, Francis - Professor, Dept. Economics, University of Pittsburgh, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  re labor clauses of NRA with copies of John Andrews letters and Rubinow; unemployment insurance legislation; Jewish situation in Germany; opposition to the AALL Act
- Ul-Un, 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  personal, financial and routine
- Unemployment Acknowledgment Letters, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  letters of thanks from Rubinow for papers on unemployment insurance from various sources
- Unemployment - Elizabeth Magee - Executive Secretary, Ohio Commission on Unemployment Insurance, 1931-33; Executive Secretary, Consumer's League of Ohio, 1933-36, 1931-1936 (Box 10, Folder 12-18)
  correspondence re legislation, committee meetings, public hearings, studies, Miss Perkins' conference re labor legislation (2/23/3U), Ohio Plan vs. Wagner Bill
- Unemployment-Ohio-Leiserson, William, 1931-1933 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  correspondence re J.F. Lincoln's statements about the three people responsible for the unemployment insurance bill not being competent (Rubinow, A.H. Silver & William Leiserson); actuarial problems of unemployment insurance plans
- Unemployment Commission-Ohio, 1930-1933 (Box 10, Folder 20-23)
  correspondence re requests for Rubinow's report on unemployment insurance; copies of minutes of meetings; publications; statistics; and routine correspondence
- Unemployment Insurance - Bills and Pamphlets, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  correspondence re pamphlets from various sources on unemployment insurance
- Unemployment Insurance - Lewis-Wagner Bill, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  correspondence re hearings on Bill; 12 pp. manuscript apparently by Rubinow, on unemployment insurance
- Unemployment Insurance - Ohio, 1931-1934 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  correspondence with Ohio Governor George White re unemployment insurance bill
- Unemployment Insurance - Pennsylvania - Legislative bill, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  proposed plan of insurance by Paul H. Douglas and miscellaneous
- Unemployment Insurance - U.S., 1930-1935 (Box 10, Folder 28-31)
  routine general correspondent re unemployment insurance
- U.S., 1906-1935 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  correspondence re Rubinow1s appointment to Social Security Board (1935); re sickness insurance report (1915) and routine
- U.S. Bureau of Labor, 1911-1917 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  correspondence re Rubinow1s resignation from the Bureau as statistician and appointment with Ocean Accident Guarantee Corporation as Chief Statistician; accident statistics study
- U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  letter from Assistant Secretary of Agriculture directing Rubinow to attend upcoming meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science in New Orleans
- University Settlement, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  one letter to Rubinow re article on shorter hours
- University's, 1930-1935 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  routine and literary correspondence
- V, 1924-1934 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  letter to Mary VanKleeck re membership in the Inter-professional Association for Social Insurance; literary and personal correspondence; correspondence with S.A. Van Vriesland, Palestine Zionist Executive
- Wa, 1908-1935 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  with Frank Warne, Secretary, NYS Commission of Immigration, re employment for Rubinow (1908) as statistician; with Eva Ward, NJ Equal Suffrage Press Committee re woman suffrage (1915); with Err;lish Walling, literary correspondence re Negro problem (1910); with Margaret Wagner, Executive Secretary, Benjamin Rose Institute re administration of aid to the aged; with Morris D. Waldman re cooperation between American Jewish Committee and American Jewish Congress; personal and routine
- Warren Brothers Co., 1935-1936 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  personal and financial
- Washington, DC, 1926-1936 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  literary and routine correspondence; with Senator Robert F. Wagner re construction relief bill (1932)
- We, 1914-1936 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  with Chaim Weizmann, Zionist Congress, re financial and routine
- Wh, 1912-1934 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  literary, personal; with Albert W. Whitney, California Industrial Accident Board re disability
- White, Clyde - Director Bureau of Social Research, Indiana University, 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  re literary, sickness insurance, Social Security Act, debate on health insurance
- Whitney, Frances - Director, Ohio State Employment Service, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  re Ohio welfare Conference arrangements
- Wi, 1913-1935 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  with Sidney Wilcox, Chief Statistician, NYS Department Of Labor re unemployment for part time employees; personal, routine and literary
- Willcox, W.F. - Professor, Cornell University, 1907-1917 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  re letter of recommendation for Rubinow for federal civil service position and also Rubinow inquiring about position at Cornell University
- Wo, 1914-1935 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  literary, personal and routine
- Wohl, Samuel, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  draft letter to President Roosevelt re social security legislation requested by the President (9/2^/35 from Roosevelt to Wohl); race discrimination in Soviet Union; literary
- World Tomorrow, 1928-1934 (Box 10, Folder 49)
- WR-Wz, 1931-1934 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Y, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  with Allen Young re grain trade with Russia (1918); literary with Yale Review re social insurance; H. Yassky, Director, Hadassah Medical Organization re recommendation for nt.fl.ff ht HmiMMnnh, financial report and routine
- Za, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Ze, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  routine literary and financial
- Zi, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  with Zionist Organization of Chicago, routine and other routine correspondence
- Zionist Medical Unit, American, 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  memoranda, March 1920, re interviews re making peace with Medical Society; physicians plot to force Rubinow's resignation as Director; attack on Rubinow's personal character; seven page typed manuscript, "Concerning Women Who Are Bored" (on Zionist letterhead); Rubinow's departing speech when leaving Hadassah Medical Organization (6 pages)
- Zionist Organization, 1928-1934 (Box 11, Folder 5-8)
  correspondence with Jacob Billikopf and many others re Rubinow's appointment as Executive Director of Zionist Organization of America and United Palestine Appeal (1928); letter of resignation as Editor of Jewish Social Service Quarterly; memo re "Appointment of Rubinow," dates Aug. 8, 1928; notice of financial problems and elimination of Rubinow's position as Executive Director and correspondence re the problem (July 1929); report of Executive Director, March 1929; &-ud routine
- Zunser, Charles, 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 1 of 17), 1895-1915 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1902; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From editor of "Narodnoe Khoziaistvo" (National Economy [approximate translation]) 3/20/1902 On publ. of an article (almost illegible).
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1903; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "Scientific Review" - about payment for an article. From: Fishtok (?) 7/2/1903.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From (?) Yakovlevicha - refers to contents of earlier correspondence; hard to make out what that is no date (from Warsaw).
  - Item 4: Letter #4, 1892; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From Natasha professions of friendship 1892.
  - Item 5: Letter #5, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From Natasha refers to Rubinov's entry into university unsigned note about family affairs from someone else no date.
  - Item 6: Letter #6, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "New Life", no date, but from the 1910's signed "Pavel Serlin" - arrangements for an article.
  - Item 7: Letter #7, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "New Life", Pavel Serlin - "article published" (1910's).
  - Item 8: Letter #8, 1897; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Signed Effrou (?) - June 2, 1897.
  - Item 9: Letter #9, 1898; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "News of the Day", July 19, 1898, signed Effrou - about Rabinov's doing work for the paper in the future.
  - Item 10: Letter #10, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Signed Effrou, no date, about Rubinov's column -"don't write so much about politics, this is Russia".
  - Item 11: Letter #11, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "The New Magazine for Everyone", no date 1910's signature illegible - a disagreement about published an article.
  - Item 12: Letter #12, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - no date - signature (and letter) basically illegible - something about Russian economy and trade with America.
  - Item 13: Letter #13, 1895; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    About the publication of a book, which will be reviewed by the writer, signed VI. Vagner (Wagner) Dec, 25 1895.
  - Item 14: Letter #14, 1896; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Packet of letters (signature illegible) about the translation of books Darwin after Darwin, and The Evolution of Sex, 1896.
  - Item 15: Letter #15, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    From "Nature", Vladimir Aleksandrovich Vagner -about translation, in same packet as (14).
  - Item 16: Letter #16, 1907; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    "Hotel Belvedere, Baltimore" letterhead July 15, 1907 signature illegible, initials P.V. - about a possible meeting.
  - Item 17: Letter #17, Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    "Hotel Rector, N.Y." letterhead, an invitation to breakfast from Ekaterina G.? - three other from same woman - acceptance of invitation to matinee, "see you tomorrow" and suchlike.
  - Item 18: Letter #18, 1903; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Request for help finding work from Avraam (?) Sept. 14, 1903.
  - Item 19: Letter #19, 1908-1912; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    5 letters in purple ink from Iosif Markovich Goldstein (from Moscow) 4 from 1908, one 1912 - all refer to literature on labor questions, mostly about topics relating to workmen's compensation.
  - Item 20: Letter #20, 1908; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    One more (from Moscow) in purple ink, same handwriting, same subject (1908).
  - Item 21: Letter #21, 1913; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Letterhead: "The New Willard, Washington, D.C.",. July 27, 1913, from Goldstein - notes about his trip in U.S. and Canada, sets meeting with Rubinov.
  - Item 22: Letter #22, 1913; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    1913, "Waldorf-Astoria, New York" - from Goldstein sets meeting.
  - Item 23: Letter #23, 1913; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    "Cosmos Club, Washington" - Aug. 1913, from Goldstein gives his address.
  - Item 24: Letter #24, 1914-1945; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    2 (back to purple ink) from Goldstein in Moscow 3/6/1914, and 6/25/1915 - references to Rubinov's family reasons for not having written, etc.
  - Item 25: Letter #25, 1910-1915; Letter (Box 11, Folder 10)
    12 letters: on the letterhead of "Editorship: Editions of the Brothers Granat and Co." - all but one signed A. Smirnov. - on publication of various things between 1910-15.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 2 of 17), 1900-1911 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1902-1904; Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    3 letters from "Russian School" (1902-1904) -on publication, two letters signed Ya. Gurevich.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1908-1909; Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    3 letters from "Russian Riches" (1908-1909) signed A. Meliokhomov (?) - acceptances of articles for publ.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Two copies, printed, from "Russian News" - asking for contributions to 50th anniversary editors.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, 1910-1911; Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    3 letters from Nikolai Vasilievich Speransky 1910-1911 (editor for "Russian News") there is mention of political reasons for the journal being unable to publish his writing.
  - Item 5: Letter #5, 1900; Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Signature illegible Moscow 1900 - about writing for an unidentified journal.
  - Item 6: Letter #6, Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    From V. Gol..(?) - about "sketches" by Rubinov.
  - Item 7: Letter #7, Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    From "Russian News", about an article on Carnegie.
  - Item 8: Letter #8, Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    From someone at "Russian School" - "less politics, please".
  - Item 9: Letter #9, Letter (Box 11, Folder 11)
    On articles.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 3 of 17), 1893-1909 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1893-1895; Letter (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Romantic Intrigue. Increasingly friendly letters, most with letterhead "S. Feigensohn, Wilna", from Masha (?). Terrible writing, (c. 1893-95).
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1893; Letter (Box 11, Folder 12)
    One letter from a jealous husband - the end and signature seem to be missing, however - from Berlin, 1893.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, 1903; Letter (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Two typed letters from an official in the ministry of foreign trade, one asking for information and the other responding to a request for payment for that information 1903.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, 1909; Letter (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Four letters from Yakov Fratkin (?) all 1909 -Something to do with help in getting a job at Library of Congress.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 4 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Many letters from official in Ministry and Finances and from editorship of "Financial Herald", all about publ.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Undated letter, illegible signature, about Rubinov's desire to translate something.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Packet of letters from journal "Sunrise" -payment for articles.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, Letter (Box 11, Folder 13)
    More letters from editors.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 5 of 17), 1902-1911 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Postcards - Some from an editor, some from someone else who also writes for journals.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Visiting card - a note with info, about someone who knows about milling flour.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Letters from Kozmin, a professor and editor of Struggling Journal "Russian Miller" - about publ.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Packet letters from Katzen, who appears to be involved with the Russian Social Democratic Society of Baltimore. First letter to Rubinov mentions a program in Kishinyov, and calls on him to uphold "the organization" by giving a lecture. - More of the same.
  - Item 5: Letter #5, 1902; Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Purple ink, end missing, 1902 - acceptance of an article.
  - Item 6: Letter #6, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Description of a reading-room in a Russian provincial city.
  - Item 7: Letter #7, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Questions about American universities. Stamped by the police from Kiyachko date illegible.
  - Item 8: Letter #8, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    From Kiyachko, who is now in jail. Asks for a Harvard University Catalogue also two postcards.
  - Item 9: Letter #9, 1911; Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Hotel de Paris, Monte Carlo letterhead 1911 - discusses an article.
  - Item 10: Letter #10, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Request for info, on American medicine.
  - Item 11: Letter #11, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    From editor of "Courier".
  - Item 12: Letter #12, Letter (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Four more postcards, mostly requests for or thanks for information.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 6 of 17), 1893-1905 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1909; Letter (Box 11, Folder 15)
    On workers in Russia 1909.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, 1893; Letter (Box 11, Folder 15)
    1893 - Congrats on matriculation.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, 1893; Letter (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Friendly correspondence - (Packet of letters, signature illegible 1893(?) - various topics of conversation.
  - Item 11: Letter #1, 1905; Letter (Box 11, Folder 15)
    A fan letter from Smolensk. 1905.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 7 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 16)
    All from editors.